Rashmi AP

Front End Web Developer, Bangalore









https://github/rashmiap



https://linkedin.com/in/rashmiap

Overview

Experienced Front-end Developer with 3+ years of experience developing and managing web apps with a demonstrated history of working in the internet industry. Skilled in ReactJS, HTML and CSS. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's Degree focussed in Computer Science from B.M.S. College of Engineering.

Experience

Roundglass ZoojooBE

Jan 2016 - present

Software Engineer

Description: Zoojoobe is a game based social wellness platform that unites the workforce to form healthier habits. The psychology behind Zoojoobe is to enable peer-to-peer motivation allowing people to challenge, cheer and reward their colleagues and friends within their organisation.

Contribution:

 We are a small tight-knit team, so I got a chance to wear many hats, from requirement analysis to generating the build.

- Worked closely with Product Managers, UX Designers and Backend Engineers to develop pixel perfect User Interface.
- Worked on various features on the App like Social feed, Dare, Pregnancy module and Journey which were developed using ReactJS on the frontend stack.
- Developed and maintained the frontend of Zoojoobe sales website.

Caterpillar Inc. Aug 2015 - Dec 2015

Associate IT Analyst

Description: Being part of Caterpillar's Global Information Services(GIS) division, features required me to work across the mainframe stack with COBOL, the primary mainframe programming language which compiles to machine language, ISPF and JCL.

Projects

ZoojooBe Social Stream

Social stream is a feature that leverages on the social behaviour within the corporate allowing users to share media among the employees within a particular corporate. It allows user to post media, like, share, comment and subscribe to a particular post that keeps them motivated to do a particular task. <u>Technology stack</u>: ReactJS, Draft-js-plugins, DropzoneJS.

ZoojooBe Dare Feature

This feature which primarily focuses on the competitive behaviour lets users throw a fun challenge to their friends on the platform and earn points for each win. It allows user to pick or customise a dare and the reward. Meanwhile other users on the platform can motivate using the cheer functionality. Technology stack: ReactJS, Material-UI, AJAX.

Zoojoobe Journey Feature

Journey feature on the Zoojoobe platform is a set of curated activities that are a set of micro-tasks that a user has to form to achieve a bigger goal like forming a complex habit. Journey feature has multiple levels which changes based on user activity. The whole task list is customised based on user activity.

<u>Technology stack</u>: ReactJS, react-sound.

Zoojoobe Pregnancy Feature

This feature is an informative and reassuring guide to pregnancy. Full of the latest essential information, relaxing audio tracks and expert advice, it helps user to prepare for motherhood.

<u>Technology stack</u>: ReactJS, react-sound.

React Redux Movies and TV shows app

This is a responsive movies and TV shows app built using ReactJS and utilizes Redux for state management. The Movie Database (TMDb) API is used to fetch data. You can navigate between the latest movies and the latest TV shows. Can view full details including cast members of each movie/TV show by clicking on 'See More' button. Can locally save and unsave any movie/TV show.

Technology stack: ReactJS, Redux, Redux-Thunk, Material-ui, TMDb api.

Github link: https://github.com/rashmiap/react-redux-TMDb-app

AudioDb Artist Search App

This is a simple mobile responsive artist search app developed using AudioDB API built using ReactJS. User can also view all the albums of each user including track additional details.

Technology stack: ReactJS, Material-ui, AudioDB API.

Github link: https://github.com/rashmiap/audioDB-react-app

Education

B M S College of Engineering, Bangalore

Computer Science and Engineering (CGPA: 9.12)

Treasurer, Fine Arts Club, 2014

2011-2015